http://www.fcs-muenchen.com/privacy-policy

Auto­motive & Transpor­tation
Auto­motive & Transpor­tation
Complex manufacturing processes and sophisticated requirements regarding durability and reliability of component parts – this is what is important in the automotive and transportation industry.
Read more
Pharma & Medical
Pharma & Medical
What is important in the pharmaceutical and medical industry? It is essential that high hy-giene standards be maintained but not at the expense of performance, reliability and eco-nomic efficiency.
Read more
Energy
Energy
Components used in power plants are subject to extreme wear. High endurance and reliability are critical factors for successful maintenance programs.
Read more
Elec­tronics & Elec­trical Engine­ering
Elec­tronics & Elec­trical Engine­ering
High performance even in small doses, high output in production as well as increased conductivity of metals – these are the major requirements for specialty chemical products in the electronics and electrical engineering industry.
Read more
Food
Food
What challenges does the food industry face? From an economic point of view, reducing processing times, saving energy and minimising waste in production rank highest on the list of requirements. At the same time, however, we want to impress the consumer with smooth and glossy coatings and an exquisite look and feel of products such as confectionery while also adhering to strict hygiene regulations.
Read more
Household & Textiles
Household & Textiles
A high degree of wearing comfort, versatility and maximum wear resistance – today we ex-pect textile products to combine all these traits. In addition, manufacturers are challenged with choosing materials that are safe for humans as well as for the environment.
Read more
Machine & Plant
Machine & Plant
Regardless of the size of components and the strain exerted on lubrication points – mechanical and plant engineering applications need extremely reliable and powerful solutions. Professional consulting services is also needed to help choose the correct solutions for particular requirements.
Read more
Heavy Indus­try
Heavy Indus­try
Extreme temperatures, continuous operation, heavy-duty loads, exposure to water, vapor, acids, saltwater, extreme wind and weather: The conditions being faced in the basic materials and heavy industry are harsh. High-quality lubricants are a must.
Read more
Mainte­nance
Mainte­nance
Enhanced energy efficiency, streamlined maintenance and production processes as well as an improved performance of machines and assemblies – all these are vital requirements in the maintenance and repair sector.
Read more
Our Solutions for YouExtending the life span of machines and systems. Providing a higher output in material processing. Delivering more functionality for textiles. Adding brilliant finishing to food. Whatever your require-ment, see for yourself which market- and application-specific solutions we can provide.
Data Protection & Privacy Policy Declaration
1. Controller
The controller, as defined in data protection law and especially the European General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), is:
Freudenberg Chemical Specialities SE & Co. KG
Geisenhausenerstraße 7
81379 Munich
Germany
Phone.: +49 89 78 76-0
info@fcs-munich.com
- also referred to in this document as “FCS“
The contact details of our data protection officer are as follows:
Data Protection Officer of Freudenberg Chemical Specialities SE & Co. KG
c/o activeMind AG
Potsdamer Str. 3
80802 Munich
Germany
Phone: +49 (0)89 / 91 92 94 – 900
FCS@activemind.de
2. What processing activities are implemented on the website?
General note concerning the recipients of data within the Freudenberg Group:
FCS is a globally active company and forms part of the Freudenberg Group. Personal data are processed by FCS employees as well as employees of other Freudenberg Group companies.
By using standard EU contracts and taking appropriate technical and organizational measures, FCS ensures that your personal data are processed in accordance with European data protection standards.
Other specific recipients are mentioned below in connection with the individual processing activities:
a. Transmission of information by email
Purpose and legal basis of processing
Your data are used for providing you with the information requested or for forwarding your enquiry for processing and a response to an appropriate body or person within the FCS Group. If your enquiry concerns a company outside the FCS Group but within the group of companies of Freudenberg & Co. KG, Weinheim, your data may be forwarded to an appropriate person or body within this group of companies. The purpose of indicating your name and, if applicable, your contact data is to allow the response to be sent to you in person if you decide to exercise your rights as a data subject.
In order to obtain the information which you require, it is sufficient for you to indicate your email address. The data provided by you will be used solely for providing the information requested by you.
Recipients:
The only recipient of your data is the controller.
Duration of storage:
In this context, the data will only be stored for the duration of information provision or other activities requested by you and will then be durably deleted.
Provision of data required:
Your personal data are only provided voluntarily, on the basis of your consent. In this context, your enquiry submitted to us concerning the provision of the information you require is deemed to be your consent.
b. Email contact
Purpose, legal basis and legitimate interests:
The data entered by you in connection with your contacts with FCS using the email address info@fcs-munich.com will only be stored temporarily for the purpose of individual communication with you. The data entered by you using the contact form will be processed on the basis of a legitimate interest (Art 6 (1) f GDPR). We provide the email address info@fcs-munich.com in order to make it easy for you to contact the company. The data which you provide will be stored for the purpose of processing your enquiry and for possible follow-up enquiries.
If you contact us to request a quotation, the data provided will be processed in connection with measures prior to entering into a contract (Art 6 (1) b GDPR).
Recipients:
Our website is maintained by a service provider.
In the event that you send us an enquiry or a quotation, service providers acting on our behalf may receive data for this purpose, in the event that the data are required for the performance of their services (e.g. IT services).
All service providers are under a contractual obligation to keep any data which they may receive confidential.
Duration of storage:
Data are deleted no later than six months after the processing of your enquiry.
In the event that a contract is concluded with you, we are subject to the statutory retention periods and will delete your data following 6 or 10 years, depending on the individual case.
Provision of data required:
Your personal data are provided voluntarily. However, we can only process your enquiry if you inform us of your name, your email address and the reason for your enquiry.
Right to object
Please read the information given below on your right to object in accordance with Art. 21 GDPR.
c. Accessing our website
Purpose, legal basis and legitimate interest:
If you access our website without registering or providing further information, certain information of a general nature will automatically be recorded. This information (server log files) may include for example the type of web browser, the operating system used, the domain name of your Internet service provider, your IP address and similar information:
This information is used for a number of purposes including the following:
ensuring the establishment of a trouble-free connection to the website,
ensuring the trouble-free use of our website,
evaluation of system security and stability and
other administrative purposes.
We also reserve the right to examine the server log files retroactively if there are specific indications of unlawful use.
We do not use your data to draw conclusions concerning your identity. We do not evaluate information of this type.
Your data are processed in accordance with Art. 6 (1) f GDPR on the basis of our legitimate interest in improving the stability and functionality of our website.
Recipients:
We call upon the services of technical service providers for the operation and maintenance of our website.
Duration of storage:
Data of the type described above are deleted as soon as they are no longer required for the purpose indicated. In the case of data required for providing the website, this is normally the case when the session concerned has ended.
Provision of data required:
The provision of the personal data mentioned above is not required by law or by contract. However, without your IP address and cookie identification, the services provided by and the functionality of our website cannot be ensured. In addition, individual services may not be available or may only be available to a limited extent.
Right to object
Please read the information given below on your right to object in accordance with Art. 21 GDPR.
d. Cookies necessary for technical reasons
Purpose, legal basis and legitimate interests
We use cookies to make our website user-friendlier. The use of cookies is necessary in order to ensure that your browser can still be identified after you have switched to another page.
Without limitation, the following data are stored and transmitted by cookies:
Language settings
The purpose of using cookies which are necessary for technical purposes is to make the utilization of our website easier for users. Some of the functions of our website cannot be used or can only be used to a limited extent without cookies. For these functions, it is necessary for the browser to be recognized even after the user has switched to another page.
We need cookies for the following applications:
Acceptance of language settings
Storage of search terms
Your data are processed in accordance with Art. 6 (1) f GDPR on the basis of our legitimate interest in the user-friendly design of our website.
Recipients of data
Your data may be received by technical service providers who are responsible for the operation and maintenance of our website.
Duration of storage and details of cookies
You will find information on the duration of storage and scope of functions of cookies in the notes made available to you via the Cookiebot tool at the beginning of your visit to our website.
Provision of data required:
The provision of the personal data mentioned above is not required by law or by contract. However, without these data, the services provided by and the functionality of our website cannot be ensured. In addition, individual services may not be available or may only be available to a limited extent.
Right to object
Please read the information given below on your right to object in accordance with Art. 21 GDPR.
Notes on cookies
As a general principle, you can of course also visit our website without cookies. The default settings of Internet browsers are normally such that they accept cookies. In general, you can deactivate the use of cookies at any time by changing the settings of your browser. Please use the help functions of your Internet browser to find out how you can change these settings. For standard browsers, information is provided below. Please note that individual functions of our website may no longer be available if you have deactivated the use of cookies.
To the extent that these cookies may also affect personal data, you will find further information in the following paragraphs.
Via your browser settings, you can also delete individual cookies or all the cookies which are stored. In addition, you will find information and instructions concerning the deletion or blockage of cookies. Depending on your browser, you will find the necessary information under the following links
Mozilla Firefox: https://support.mozilla.org/de/kb/cookies-loeschen-daten-von-websites-entfernen
Internet Explorer: https://support.microsoft.com/de-de/help/17442/windows-internet-explorer-delete-manage-cookies
Google Chrome: https://support.google.com/accounts/answer/61416?hl=de
Opera: http://www.opera.com/de/help
Safari: https://support.apple.com/kb/PH17191?locale=de_DE&viewlocale=de_DE
e. Cookies which are not required for technical reasons
Purpose and legal basis
In some cases, our websites also use “cookies”. Cookies are a standard technology consisting of small text files which are stored on your device and which allow visits to a website to be made more convenient or safer. Cookies can also be used to ensure that the services offered on a website are more effectively harmonized with the user’s interests or to generally improve the offering on the basis of statistical evaluations.
Further information on the cookies we use is given in the cookie tool “Cookiebot“, which you will see at the beginning of your visit to our website.
The legal basis for these processing activities is your consent in accordance with Art. 6 (1) a GDPR.
Recipients of data
Your data may be received by technical service providers who are responsible for the operation and maintenance of our website.
You will find information on further recipients and the functioning of the tools that are used in our tool “Cookiebot“.
Duration of storage and details of cookies
You will find details on the duration of storage and scope of functions of cookies in the notes which are made available to you at the beginning of your visit to our website via the “Cookiebot“ tool under the heading “procedure” or “purpose”.
Profiling
the behavior of visitors to our website can be assessed and their interests can be analyzed using tracking tools. On this basis, we generate a pseudonymized user profile.
f. Use of Google Maps
Purpose and legal basis
We use the service offered by Google Maps on this website. Google Maps is operated by Google LLC, 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA (referred to below as “Google”). This allows us to display interactive maps on our website and to make convenient map functions available to you.
You will find further information on data processing by Google in the Google privacy policy. You can also change your personal data protection settings in the data protection center which you can access via this link.
You will find detailed information on the administration of your own data in connection with Google products here.
The legal basis for these processing activities is your consent in accordance with Art. 6 (1) a GDPR.
Recipients:
As a result of your visit to the website, Google receives information on the fact that you have called up the appropriate page in our website. This happens irrespective of whether Google makes available a user account which you have used for logging in or you have no user account. If you are logged on to Google, your data will be assigned directly to your account.
Objection to processing:
If you do not wish your data to be assigned to your Google profile, you must log off from Google before activating the button. Google stores your data as user profiles and uses them for advertising purposes, market research and/or the design of its website in line with demand. Such evaluations are made especially (even for users who are not logged in) for the purpose of providing advertising in line with demand and informing other users of the social network concerning your activities on our website. You are entitled to object to the formation of these user profiles. In order to exercise this right, you must submit your objection to Google.
Duration of storage:
We do not collect any personal data as a result of the integration of Google Maps.
Transfer to other countries:
Google processes your data in the USA and has subjected itself to the EU_US Privacy Shield https://www.privacyshield.gov/EU-US-Framework.
Prevention of processing:
If you do not wish Google to receive, process or use data concerning you via our website, you can deactivate JavaScript in your browser settings. However, in this case, you may be unable to use our website or only able to use our website to a limited extent.
Provision of data required:
The provision of your personal data is not required by law or by contract. However, without these data, the functions of the website may be limited.
3. Data security
We only process personal data to the extent that this is possible in accordance with data protection legislation. We also use our best efforts to take all the technical and organizational measures which may be necessary to provide adequate protection for your personal data against unauthorized access and misuse at all times.
To ensure the security of your data during transmission, we use encryption procedures (e.g. SSL) via HTTPS. Our servers are protected by firewalls and antivirus software. Backup and recovery procedures as well as role and authorization concepts are part of our policy.
In the handling of your data, our employees are under an obligation to observe the requirements of the GDPR and the BDSG (German Federal Data Protection Act).
4. What are your data protection rights?
All data subjects have a right of access in accordance with Art. 15 GDPR, a right to rectification in accordance with Art. 16 GDPR, a right to erasure in accordance with Art. 17 GDPR, a right to restriction of processing in accordance with Art. 18 GDPR, a right to object in accordance with Art. 21 GDPR and a right to data portability in accordance with Art. 20 GDPR.
The right of access and the right to erasure are subject to the restrictions provided for in Articles 34 and 35 BDSG.
You may withdraw your consent to the processing of your personal data at any time. This also applies to declarations of consent given before the General Data Protection Regulation came into force, i.e. before May 25, 2018. Please note that the withdrawal of consent is only effective for the future and does not affect data processing which has taken place before we receive the withdrawal of your consent.
Furthermore, you have a right to lodge a complaint with the supervisory authority (Art. 77 GDPR in conjunction with Article 19 BDSG). You will find a list of supervisory authorities (for the non-public sector) together with their addresses at
https://www.bfdi.bund.de/DE/Infothek/Anschriften_Links/anschriften_links-node.html
5. Changes in our data protection provisions
We reserve the right to change this data protection declaration in order to reflect the legal provisions in force at any time or changes in our services, e.g. in connection with the introduction of new services. When you next visit our website, the new data protection declaration will then apply.
6. Information on your right to object in accordance with Art. 21 GDPR
Right subject to individual cases
You have the right to object at any time, for reasons connected with your individual situation, to the processing of your personal data on the basis of Art. 6 (1) f GDPR (data processing on the basis of balancing of interests), including profiling based on these provisions in accordance with Art. 4 No. 4 GDPR.
If you submit an objection, we will no longer process your personal data unless we can demonstrate compelling legitimate grounds for processing which override your interests, rights and freedoms or processing is required for the establishment, exercise or defense of legal claims.
Recipient of objection
You do not need to observe any special form for your objection. Your objection should be sent to the contact data of the controller given in Section 1 above with the subject of “Objection”.
